For this second exercise, we're going to practice our Comprehensions, our List Comprehensions
and more.
We're also going to take a closer look at slicing and use the zip function.
Okay, so we talked about all sorts of different types of Comprehensions.
Comprehension looks something like this.
I can say, you know, give me all the even numbers from 0 to 99 by looping through and saying
4-NOM, let me say, 4-NOM in range of 100.
And going back to the beginning, I know that I just want the number, I don't want anything
special with it.
If I wanted to get just the even numbers, I would do a modular check and say that if the
modulo 2 is 0, that's even.
One important thing to remember here is that you have to use the equality operator to check
that the value is explicitly 0.
Otherwise, it's going to be falsie and you're going to get the odd values instead.
Okay, there we go.
I'm going to assign this to a variable.
And I'm going to use something from the standard library.
The random method is going to help me get a random number.
In the wrap-all, you can type import random, but know that when you do imports in Python
files, you always want to put your imports at the top.
And as an aside, there's a command in the command palette called Organize imports.
Once you start making Python files with a lot of imports, it'll just organize them in a really
nice way for you.
So I want to make a dictionary where the key is the random, the key is the number.
And then the value is just a random number from I0 to 99.
So to get a random number, I can say random dot random int.
And let's say I didn't remember what this method did or with the arguments were, what
can I use to give me a little bit of guidance to help my third year?
So I can pass this whole thing into help.
I'll say random, A and B, return a random integer in the range of A and B, including both
and points.
So I'll call random dot random int, 0 to 100, and call this multiple times, get new
value each time that's random.
So for my dictionary, I'm going to make a dictionary comprehension.
And what's the difference between syntax between a dictionary comprehension and a set
comprehension?
The colon, right?
So on the left side of the colon is my key.
And on the right side, I'm going to use this random dot random int from 0 to 100.
What am I looping over?
Right, well, so I'm going to say for none in my list.
And taking a look at my deck, there we go.
Each value is a random number.
Let me look at the values that we're generated.
You can do that with my deck dot values.
And it's likely that there are some duplicates here, not entirely sure, right?
The number is a random.
So if I wanted to quickly deduplicate this data structure, there's two ways that I could
do it.
The first would be to pass it into a set.
Or I could use a set comprehension, too.
Let's say I wanted to make some modifications before I dedupt it.
That would be a good use for a set comprehension.
So here I could just say for none.
Number none in my deck dot values.
Oops, sorry about that.
There we go.
And that'll do the same thing.
For slicing, I'm going to make a new list.
I can, with the numbers from 0 to 99.
As we saw, I can do that in two ways.
I could, if I have the range from 0 to 100, I can pass this into list.
Or if I wanted to make some modifications to it, then a list comprehension would be a good
way.
I could just say, you know, number none in range of 100.
And you know, my modifications would be here, but I'm just going to show you this as an example.
I'm going to name this my list.
And I'm going to take a slice of the list.
In the wrap-all, it's easy to see the slicing as you go.
So the first thing I want to do is take a slice from the 30th value to the 69th one.
If I wanted to do the same slice, but take every other value instead, what is the
third parameter I can pass, or I can add here, every other, that would give me every
other one.
If I had my list here, and I wanted to take, get all the values in it, but just in reverse,
what is a shortcut using slicing?
All in colon, negative one.
From the introduction to Python course, what's another way that we can reverse all of the
values in a list?
That reverse, yeah, I can say, my list dot reverse does the same thing.
What is the difference here?
Does this didn't return anything, right?
Sorted in place.
Sorted in place, while this returns a copy.
Okay, I'm going to dot reverse my list one more time so that we end up with the same thing.
If I wanted to return a reverse copy of the list with one other way that I can do it.
So that's not quite right.
It will work on this sorted or this list of numbers, but that's because they're all already
in order.
Just to keep in mind that when we use that dot reverse and this, this syntax will return
the list backwards, but if you use dot sort or sorted and pass in the reverse flag,
it's going to do a descending sort.
So hard to see with a list of numbers, but easier to see with other types of data structures.
Okay, let's talk about zip.
We have Nina Max, we have Floyd, and we have Lloyd, and they all have some scores in a game.
Let's use random again here, and ask for a random integer between 0 and 100, and I'm going
to loop through each name.
Oh, no, I'm losing.
Okay, so if I wanted to zip up these values, I can say four name and score in the zip of names
and scores, and print out an app string that says, you know, name, got scores, points, oh, um,
you want score, score, score, score, score, score. Thank you.
Group pair programming is always the quickest way. Okay, there we go.
What if I wanted a dictionary of these names to their scores?
I can just pass that zip into the deduct constructor and end up with that.
Someone asked a really good question while they were doing the exercise, and so I wanted to review
that very quickly so that we're all clear on it. So if I look at the zip of names and scores,
and get back something that looks like this, this is usually a hint that this type of object
might be a what? Yeah, it might be a generator. And note this is kind of for
these built-in types. If you make your own classes and you don't put in a string representation,
you might also see something that looks like this, but it's not a generator. We just
didn't go through with, you know, putting a representation function in there.
If I, then assign this to a variable. So I'm going to show you what happens when a generator
is exhausted. What's that? I'm going to say that my zip is the zip of the names and the scores.
If I loop through this, and I'm just going to say for Z and my zip, print out Z, and it went through,
each tuple and the list printed it out. We know that these generator expressions, they only know
kind of their current value, that they're returning, and they know just the next step in the
future. They don't know anything about the past, and they can't, they can't see far ahead into the
future. So if I print out, if I print out, if I try to do this again and say,
for Z and my zip print Z, what do you think I'll see? Nothing. Why is that? It's because
used it up as what you go through? Yeah, I've already used it up. It's empty. It knew that, you know,
the last step was, it finished the last step, and then it's gone. There's nothing more in it.
So you can't reuse these generators. They're kind of a one-time use sort of thing.